It's been five days since the satellite fell onto
the Akihabara Radio Building.
Since morning, many people have gathered here
again today to see it.
But the satellite's origins remain unknown,
and there's no timetable for when it will be taken down.
Mail Received
Could I have a moment?
Are you here to see the satellite?
Would you tell us where you've come from?
Even the number of several billion heartbeats
suujuuoku mo no kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
is basic research with little glamor for you
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
Even locked in the past and lamenting the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
it's an inevitability that won't forgive miscalculating one speck of dust
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The dreams that stretch out forever and the future we imagine
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
are a vain theory we allowed
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finity, that's what the two hands of the clock point out
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
towards a cruel agreement and choice
Hacking to the Gate
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
That's why I want to cross world lines with each passing second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
and protect your smile
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no loop e to
And once again, into a time loop that contains no sadness
nomikomareteyuku kodoku no kansokusha
A swallowed solitary observer
Butterfly Effect's Divergence
This is it?
It's delicious!
Miss Amane, you've never had gyuudon?
No. I'd heard rumors of it.
It's delicious.
It's even better if you put a raw egg on it.
If you call yourself a warrior,
you should be able to come to a gyuudon place by yourself.
Well, Daru and I come here often.
If you invite us, we'll go with you anytime.
I remember!
Last time, I had to pay for Okarin's meal.
It's possible that happened, yes.
It's not just possible! It happened!
Give me back my money!
Sadly, I've none on me today.
It's me.
Transfer the funds to my Swiss bank account.
What?
The Organization hacked into the Geneva servers?
No cell phones.
How terrible...
Um, he's just pretending.
So you were with them, too, Suzu-san?
It was time for my lunch break.
If you'd been a bit earlier, you could've joined us.
Then, you want to all go together tomorrow?
I'm sure Okarin would be happy to pay—
What?
The Organization's sabotaging the process,
and it will take one week to bring the servers back online?
It's Kurisu-chan!
Assistant, did you get some sleep?
Don't call me assistant.
Hey, part-timer.
If you're done with lunch, get back to work.
What's with her?
A round table?
Indeed.
What's that?
A meeting of lab members.
We ever do one before?
Do you even own a round table?
Not a physical one.
But the round table lies within all lab members' hearts.
Right?
Whether it's true or not,
don't put anything weird in my heart.
Do you think there's one in Mayushii's heart, too?
Yes, there is.
Is there?
Yay!
But what's a round table?
Why a round table?
Are you supposed to be King Arthur?
I'm only a temporary lab member anyway.
At any rate...
It's time for a round table.
We need to tell Mayuri about the situation we find ourselves in.
Situation?
And so,
in order to beat SERN, we must perfect
the Phone Microwave (name subject to change)
as soon as possible.
It's too hard for Mayushii to understand!
Just know that SERN is evil.
But how do we perfect it?
We've succeeded in sending messages to the past, right?
Only twice!
And we don't know under what conditions
the phenomenon occurs.
From what we observed last time,
it only occurs when there's electricity.
Right!
Did you find out something?
No. "Mails Sent to the Past" is too long.
First, we need to find a name for them.
Another failed attempt to sound leet?
Don't say "another"!
Do you dare mock the great Hououin—
You'll just give it a stupid name anyway.
How rude!
Then I'll tell you.
I've given this name to the phenomenon of e-mails going back in time...
I call it "Nostalgia Drive"!
You write it with the kanji for "journey crossing over time,"
but you read it "Nostalgia Drive."
Too complicated.
Rejected.
Hey, you're the assistant, you can't reject—
Then let's have a vote.
Who agrees with "Nostalgia Drive"?
Et tu, Mayuri? Daru?
I think Kurisu-chan is right.
Mayushii can't remember a long name like that.
It's like something invented by an emo teenager fixated on sci-fi.
We should focus on making it easy to understand.
Since it's an e-mail going back in time,
we could call it "Mail That Flies Against Time."
What's "flies against time"?
That's not easy to understand at all.
It should be "The Mail That Leapt Through Time."
It's a bit formal.
And hard to say.
You don't get to say that.
Your "Nostalgia whatsit" was long, too!
It's romantic! If it's romantic, it's okay!
So we can shorten it to TimeLeap.
Then we don't know what leapt through time!
Is it an e-mail? A girl? A banana?
Mayushii has an idea!
Um... "Back to the Mail"!
That would be going back to the e-mail, not back in time.
That doesn't make sense.
Then "DeLorean Mail"!
That makes even less sense!
Hey...
Why don't we just shorten it to "D-mail"?
I like that.
Okay, it's decided then.
We will now begin the experiments with D-mail (name subject to change).
We can also cut the "(name subject to change)."
The operation is called Operation Urd.
We don't need that, either.
But we don't know what it takes to make the D-mail happen.
Or what it's got to do with electricity.
That's what we're going to find out.
I, Hououin Kyouma, have an idea.
We forgot the simplest and most important condition.
In other words, the time it occurred!
The first D-mail was between 12:00 and 13:00.
The second occurred around 18:00.
If we attempt to replicate it at those times,
we will succeed.
Possibly.
That's gotta be too simple.
It's worth trying.
Mayuri, the banana!
Mayushii's running low on bananas.
Do we have to put the banana in?
"Put the banana in!"
Daru, not now.
I want to see if it turns into a jellyman.
Now, assistant.
Put the banana inside.
"Put the banana inside"...
Enough, you pervert!
I'm sorry.
I'll buy you a new banana later.
Really?
I'm so happy!
Okarin and Daru never buy me any.
Jeez, you two...
Ow!
Stop trying to show what a klutz you are.
I'm not!
Pain, pain, go away!
Thanks, Mayuri.
Stop making a Yuri Field and prepare the D-mail.
Right.
Is 120 seconds okay for the time?
Indeed.
Begin Operation Urd!
Now!
It's here.
It's here!
Where's the banana?
It's a gel-bana!
I've solved it at last.
As I thought,
time was the D-mail's missing factor!
Nice job, Okabe.
It was so simple, I didn't notice.
Does it bother you?
Still, I respect you for having the guts to gaze upon me so admiringly.
Anyway, did the D-mail arrive?
It did.
It says it was sent five days ago.
Did you send two messages, Miss Makise?
No, just one.
It's split into two messages.
By the way, what does this message mean?
Look it up yourself.
Come to think of it,
the last D-mail was also split into multiple messages,
and some of it was lost.
And it went back in time five days, too.
Yeah, there's some kind of rule to it.
Which means that D-mail...
...was calling me an empty-headed idiot?
Took you a while.
Curse you, Christina. Taking advantage of a...
Wait a minute. Why are you buying so much?
The only food we need is non-perishable cup ramen.
One bag of the cheap chocolate is plenty.
I'm celebrating our experiment's success.
Go put it back.
Cheap-ass.
That's right.
I was so happy about the experiment's success, I forgot.
We learned SERN's terrifying secret.
And I even involved Mayuri.
Was this really for the best?
It's Shining Finger.
What?
What are you doing?
You don't have your cell phone?
The great Hououin Kyouma's cell phone is
currently being used for an experiment that will be remembered throughout history.
It's not here.
O-O-Okarin!
Who's that sweet-ass...
I mean sexy... 3D girl?
I'll introduce you.
This is Shining Finger, Kiryuu Moeka.
H-Hi, Kiryuu
Even I once had hope for the 3D world.
Yo!
Are you guys doing something fun?
Indeed.
We are performing an experiment that will become legendary.
Legendary is fine...
But the boss is really pissed off.
He says the vibrations from the second story are really bad.
"I'll raise your rent 10,000 yen!"
he was saying.
10,000 yen?
Okay, leave this to me.
Tell my assistant to stop the experiments for a moment, Daru.
Roger.
You're shining like never before...
Is Makise Kurisu still there?
Oh, yeah. You were staring at her back there, weren't you?
So, what happened earlier?
What's your deal with her?
Did something happen in the past?
Nothing in the past, no.
Yes, it was the summer we were eight.
And on the dry riverbed of the Mississippi,
your red-eared slider ran away—
It was nothing!
I saw her for the first time earlier!
Anyway, you should go see the boss.
What are you doing upstairs?
It's been shaking like an earthquake.
We're performing an experiment that will rewrite scientific history.
But don't worry.
We won't do any more today...
I said stop!
What are you doing?
Miss Makise said to let her do it just once more.
I sent you a message. Did you see it?
Of course not!
I warned you five days ago...
Don't be stupid!
Oh, when we weren't doing the experiments,
your phone went off a bunch of times.
A
Shining Finger
Really!
A
Shining Finger
Sorry!
A
Shining Finger
Are you maybe...
A
Shining Finger
How've you been?
A
Shining Finger
?
A
Shining Finger
Well?
A
Shining Finger
Sorry!
Are you maybe...
Shining Finger
How've you been?
?
Shining Finger
Well?
Hey
How've you been?
Okabe-kun
A
Shining Finger
Well?
Find out anything about
the IBN 5100?
Why didn't she just ask me?!
What's wrong?
I don't know,
but he's probably not getting enough calcium.
Whose fault is that?
Well, I got plenty of data,
and I pretty much figured out the rules for how the D-mail works.
What?
A
∙ Send a modified command to the microwave's heading function (reverse spin)
∙ Open the microwave door while heating (Timing -> Unconfirmed)
->
Electricity
∙ While the electricity is sparking, send message to the phone
∙ Prerequisites to making the electricity appear? (time between 12:00 PM and 18:00 PM?)
∙ Number of characters that can be sent
with a D-mail -> (12 half-width, 6 full-width) x3
∙ You can control the time the Phone Microwave
(name subject to change) sends a message back.
One second on the timer = One hour in reality
∙ At the same time, anything placed into the Phone Microwave becomes a jellyman
(teleportation confirmed, as well)
Each second on the timer represents one hour back in time.
120 seconds is 5 days.
It's amazing that she figured out how to control how far it goes back, isn't it?
But the maximum amount of information that can be sent back is 36 English characters
or 18 Japanese characters.
It's too small.
I'd like to fix that.
I'm sure you can't send anything too big,
or send too much.
Maybe that Curb black hole...
The Kerr black hole, right.
The hole is too tight!
Can you repeat that, Mayushii?
The part about the hole?
Shut up, pervert!
Anyhow, we can work on the details tomorrow and going forward.
But I'll say this:
August 2, 2010,
is a day that mankind will remember forever!
For the Future Gadget Lab
has succeeded in developing humanity's
first time machine!
It's not the first one, right?
SERN beat us.
We didn't "develop" it, anyway.
It was all coincidence.
All of you, disrespecting my great declaration...
But Okarin...
I'm glad your experiments worked.
Where am I?
You're not moving.
Time and space have changed places here.
The event horizon?
You can't move through space.
And time is extended forever.
One second of your time will be an eternity for me.
The end of space is running away?
No, it's not. It's being extended.
What is?
The universe?
Or me?
You mustn't look back.
Eternity isn't infinite.
Even if time extends toward eternity,
an end still exists.
When will it be one second later?
Look forward.
Reach the end.
You mustn't turn back.
That mail freak again?
Her persistence...
A
Shining Finger
You there?
A
Shining Finger
It's dark
A
Shining Finger
Wake up
A
Shining Finger
I'm here
A
Shining Finger
You asleep?
A
Shining Finger
It bug you?
A
Shining Finger
It bug you?
Sorry for yesterday
Moeka
Sorry for yesterday.
Can I come see you?
I'm here
At least answer me.
Or are you pretending not to be there?
Moeka
A
Shining Finger
It didn't occur to you that I was asleep?
Wake up
Were you asleep?
Moeka
I was!
A
Shining Finger
It's dark
I'm coming up the stairs right now.
Moeka
What?
A
Shining Finger
I'm outside
I'll knock. If you're there, respond.
Moeka
You said I could come see, right?
Why use your cell phone?
I'm right here.
I'm not looking at it. Just say it.
I can show you, but I didn't think you'd come this early.
I get it!
You're really after an interview with me, aren't you?
Why don't you talk?
I see... So that's it.
You're terrified of Mad Scientist Hououin Kyouma's sinister aura!
It's easier to send mails...
So show me the IBN 5100.
Very well.
But I'm just showing it to you.
Once you've seen it, leave!
Is that all right?
Is she just a retro-PC fan?
Let me take a picture
Moeka
But not my face.
If you photograph my face,
I'll have to silence you forever...
Please!
I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?
I'd be happy if you'd help me carry it.
Moeka
I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?
I'd be happy if you'd help me carry...
Why am I suddenly lending it to you?
And if you really want me to loan it to you,
then look at me and say it.
You'll loan it to me?
Sadly, no.
I'm only borrowing it myself.
When I'm done,
I have to return it to its original owner.
Its original owner?
Yanabayashi Shrine.
Guten Morgen.
You're Miss Kiryuu from yesterday, right?
I didn't introduce you yesterday, did I?
My favorite right arm, Super Haker Daru.
It's "Hacker," man. Seriously.
Anyway, I thought I'd improve the Phone Microwave a little.
It's currently a bit of a pain in the ass, right?
Sending the D-mails to the past.
What does he mean, "sending
mails to the past"?
Moeka
I-It's nothing.
You misheard.
He didn't say, "sending mails to the past."
He said, "Sen Dingma Ils Tot Hepast,"
which is ancient Sumerian for "Did you eat breakfast?"
Good morning, Okarin!
Can Mayushii use the microwave before you to make her kara-age?
Okabe, I had an idea about the time machine.
It's me.
This is bad.
No.
Information about #8 has been leaked to a third party.
What's going on?
He's totally ignoring all three of us?
We can't let the Organization find out...
Don't mail while I'm on the phone!
Was that maybe...
It can't be FB?
FB?
Very well. I'll tell you everything.
Since you've found out, there's nothing else I can do.
Kiryuu Moeka,
from now on, you're Lab Member 005!
kisei sareta chikai mujihi nari juuni no shinri nogarerarenai
We cannot escape the 12 merciless truths and the controlled oath we took
ansoku no asu wo negattara
If we wish for a tomorrow full of rest
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
to be given to the precious event horizon in our hands
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
the promise we made in captivity turns out to be a phantom
seimei no tenshi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
The angel of life recorded a time of blindness
habatake butterfly
A flapping butterfly
kiseki no butterfly
A miraculous butterfly
anata he sasageru
I will consecrate them to you
namida no butterfly
Butterflies of tears
mabushii butterfly
Dazzling butterflies
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
All those are being rewritten